JINGYAN WANG

334 Groseclose Building, 755 Ferst Drive NW, Atlanta, GA 30332

Web: https://jingyanw.github.io/ Email: jingyanw@gatech.edu Phone: 510-604-2427

RESEARCH OVERVIEW

My research interests are in *statistical machine learning* and *fairness*. Specifically, my research studies the foundations of high-stakes decision-making and evaluation processes, such as hiring, admissions and peer review. I consider three components that play critical roles in such processes — algorithms, people, and policies. I draw inspirations from psychology to model real-world phenomena, develop theoretical guarantees using tools from statistics and computer science, conduct crowdsourcing experiments, and implement policy changes that have practical impacts.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Georgia Institute of Technology 2021 – present Ronald J. and Carol T. Beerman President's Postdoctoral Fellow

Algorithms and Randomness Center (ARC) Postdoctoral Fellow
H. Milton Stewart School of Industrial and Systems Engineering

Host: Ashwin Pananjady

Simons Institute for the Theory of Computing

11.2021

Visiting postdoc

Program: Computational Complexity of Statistical Inference

EDUCATION

Carnegie Mellon University 2015 – 2021

Ph.D. in Robotics

Master of Science in Robotics

Thesis: "Towards Understanding and Mitigating Biases"

Advisor: Nihar B. Shah

University of California, Berkeley

2011 - 2015

2015

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering and Computer Sciences

Minor in Mathematics

Graduated with Highest Honors

AWARDS

Rising Stars in Data Science Workshop, University of Chicago	2022
Best Lightning Talk from College of Engineering, Fall 2022 Georgia Tech Postdoc Research Symposium	2022
Best Research Talk from College of Engineering, Spring 2022 Georgia Tech Postdoc Research Symposium	ı 2022
Ronald J. and Carol T. Beerman President's Postdoctoral Fellowship, Georgia Tech	2021
ARC (Algorithms & Randomness Center) Fellowship, Georgia Tech	2021
Best Paper Award Nomination, AAMAS 2019	
Best Student Paper Award, AAMAS 2019	

best Student Paper Award, AAMAS 2019

Travel scholarship, AAAI 2020, AAMAS 2019, WiML and HCML workshops at NeurIPS 2019

Departmental Citation, UC Berkeley

Recognition of outstanding undergraduate achievement within the department awarded to one graduating senior annually

James H. Eaton Memorial Scholarship, UC Berkeley For a keen sense of creativity and inventiveness	2015
Kevin K. Gong Memorial Scholarship for Bright Minds and Big Hearts, UC Berkeley For passion about using technology to better the world	2015
Arthur M. Hopkin Award, UC Berkeley For seriousness of purpose and high academic achievement	2014
Berkeley Club of Hong Kong Undergraduate Scholarship, UC Berkeley	2014
Edward Frank Kraft Award for Freshmen, UC Berkeley	2012

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS AND UNDER REVIEW

- Jingyan Wang, Ashwin Pananjady
 Modeling and Correcting Bias in Sequential Evaluation
 Under review at Operations Research, 2022.
- Jingyan Wang, Ivan Stelmakh, Yuting Wei, Nihar B. Shah
 Debiasing Evaluations That Are Biased by Evaluations

 Accepted with minor revisions at Journal of Machine Learning Research (JMLR), 2022.

CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS (* indicates authors in alphabetical order)

- Austin Xu, Andrew D. McRae, Jingyan Wang, Mark A. Davenport, Ashwin Pananjady
 Parametric Adjustment Queries: A New Paradigm for Human Data Elicitation with Applications to Metric
 Learning
 Working paper, 2023.
- Jingyan Wang, Ashwin Pananjady
 Modeling and Correcting Bias in Sequential Evaluation ACM Conference on Economics and Computation (EC), 2023.
- Gregory Kehne*, Ariel D. Procaccia*, Jingyan Wang*
 Recruitment Strategies That Take a Chance
 The Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS), 2022.
- Jingyan Wang, Carmel Baharav, Nihar B. Shah, Anita Williams Woolley, R. Ravi *Allocation Schemes in Analytic Evaluation: Applicant-Centric Holistic or Attribute-Centric Segmented?* AAAI Conference on Human Computation and Crowdsourcing (HCOMP), 2022.
- Komal Dhull, Jingyan Wang, Nihar B. Shah, Yuanzhi Li, R. Ravi
 A Heuristic for Statistical Seriation

 The Conference on Uncertainty in Artificial Intelligence (UAI), 2021.
- Jingyan Wang, Ivan Stelmakh, Yuting Wei, Nihar B. Shah Debiasing Evaluations That Are Biased by Evaluations AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2021.
- Jingyan Wang, Nihar B. Shah, R. Ravi Stretching the Effectiveness of MLE from Accuracy to Bias for Pairwise Comparisons International Conference on Artificial Intelligence and Statistics (AISTATS), 2020.
- Jingyan Wang, Nihar B. Shah *Your 2 is My 1, Your 3 is My 9: Handling Arbitrary Miscalibrations in Ratings*International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2019.

Best Student Paper Award

Nomination for Best Paper Award

Appeared as "Ranking and Rating Rankings and Ratings" at AAAI 2020 Sister Conference Track.

- Jingyan Wang, Olga Russakovsky, Deva Ramanan
 The More You Look, the More You See: towards General Object Understanding through Recursive Refinement
 Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2018.
- KV Rashmi, Preetum Nakkiran, Jingyan Wang, Nihar B. Shah, Kannan Ramchandran Having Your Cake and Eating It Too: Jointly Optimal Codes for I/O, Storage and Network-bandwidth in Distributed Storage Systems.

Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST), 2015.

Picked as the Best Paper by StorageMojo

Lei Tian, Jingyan Wang, Laura Waller
 3D differential phase-contrast microscopy with computational illumination using an LED array
 Optics Letters 39, 1326-1329, 2014.

TALKS

Understanding and Improving Evaluation: People, Algorithms, and Design Control of the	2022	
Ethics & Algorithms Seminar, University of California, Santa Cruz	2023	
Peking University	2023	
Carnegie Mellon University	2022	
Modeling and Correcting Bias in Sequential Evaluation		
Rising Stars in Data Science Workshop, University of Chicago	2022	
INFORMS Annual Meeting	2022	
Information Theory and Applications Workshop (ITA)	2022	
 Debiasing Evaluations That Are Biased by Evaluations 		
Women in EconCS, International Joint Conference on Theoretical Computer Science (IJTCS)	2021	
Towards Understanding and Mitigating Biases		
Georgia Institute of Technology	2021	
Harvard University	2021	
Nanyang Technological University	2021	
Peking University	2019	
Tening emiterally	2017	
Understanding Biases in Assessment Problems		
The Auton Lab, Carnegie Mellon University	2019	
• The More You Look, the More You See: Towards General Object Understanding through Recursive Refinement		
National Robotics Engineering Center (NREC)	2017	
rational Robbits Engineering Center (1905)	2017	

SERVICE

Reviewer: FAccT (2023), Journal of Artificial Intelligence Research (2022, 2023), Annals of Statistics (2020), ISIT (2021), AAAI (2021, 2022, 2023), STOC (2020), WiML NeurIPS (2019)

Program committee member: HCOMP (2022, 2023), Learning with Strategic Agents workshop, AAMAS (2022)

Qualifier committee member: Subhodeep Mitra (MS in Robotics, 2019)

Undergraduate student mentoring: Komal Dhull, Carmel Baharav

High school student mentoring: Charlotte Zhou (Bronx High School of Science, NY)

Admissions committee member: Robotics Institute Summer Scholars (2019)

Student volunteer: AAAI (2020), AAMAS (2019), ICML (2016)

OUTREACH

Speaker, Seminar on Diversity, Equity, Inclusion (DEI) and Bias, GT INFORMS Student Chapter	2022
Presenter, Mission Possible Summer Camp, Georgia Tech Led activities for high-school students in the summer camp to learn about industrial engineering research	2022
Grand award judge, Regeneron International Science and Engineering Fair (ISEF)	2022
Panelist, Tea with Summer Undergraduates, CMU	2019
Interview participant, the Girls Who Code Featured in the article https://womenincs.github.io/future.html	2019
Student volunteer, PhD student open house, CMU	2019, 2021
Graduate student mentor, Robitics Institute Summer Scholars (RISS), CMU Mentored undergraduate students through the graduate school application process and provided suggestions on the write	2018 ting material
Outreach officer and webmaster, Society of Women Engineers (SWE) Organized middle and high school outreach events and designed the chapter's website	2011 – 2015
Member, Eta Kappa Nu Honor Society (HKN)	2013 – 2015
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	
• Guest lecturer	
IST402 (Crowdsourcing and Crowd-AI Systems), Penn State	Spring 2023
PIC 16B (Python with Applications II), UCLA	Winter 2023
ISYE 6740 (Computational Data Analysis), Georgia Tech	Fall 2022
• Teaching assistant, 16-720 (Computer Vision), CMU	Fall 2017
• Lab assistant, EE 20N (Signals and Systems), UC Berkeley	Fall 2013
INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE	
Facebook Inc. Software Engineering Intern, Privacy Infrastructure Team	2014 – 8.2014
EMC Corporation Software Engineering Intern, Advanced Storage Division 6.2	013 – 8.2013